

# Ayşe Aker Tütüncü

Full-Stack Developer

O Utrecht, Netherlands O akerayse@gmail.com



### Summary

Hi, I'm Ayse, a Full-Stack Developer based in Utrecht. I graduated from software engineering and carried out my professional career as a business analyst and technical product manager. I worked with banks and fintech companies, improving my skills in understanding client needs, creating a scope of work in agreement with the client. After moving to the Netherlands, I decided to go back to my software engineering roots and pursue my career as a developer. Now, I am working in BNIT as a full-stack Java developer, via SALT. Outside of work, I enjoy travelling, cooking, painting and listening to music.

# **Work Experience**

#### SALT - Full-Stack Java Developer

https://salt.dev

September 2023 - Present

Amsterdam, Netherlands

Consultant at BNIT

- Involved in full stack development and also testing, DevOps, and architectural decision-making processes
- Working on healthcare systems, building a web portal for patients and doctors
- For backend; Java 17, Spring Boot 3, Spring Security 6, MySQL, JUnit, Testcontainers
- For frontend; React, Typescript, Material UI components, Vite
- DevOps; Azure Cloud, Azure DevOps, CI/CD pipelines, Docker

## **DgPays - Technical Product Manager**

September 2021 - April 2023

https://dgpays.com

Istanbul, Turkey

- Gather client requirements, write scope documents, and collaborate with IT, analysis, and software teams
- Own and manage Direct Carrier Billing (DCB) and Insurance API Gateway products
- DCB responsibilities include integrating with mobile operators, transaction processing, reconciliation, fraud/risk analysis, and merchant onboarding
- Deeply involved in DCB analysis and testing processes
- Insurance product integration with Türkiye Sigorta and management of DASK, traffic and vehicle insurances, offer and policy creation and management, cancellations, request management, and integration with PTT.

## **Intertech - Senior Business Analyst**

November 2020 - September 2021

https://intertech.com.tr

Istanbul, Turkey

Worked in the ATM team

- Involved in planning, analysis, and testing of ATM functions for multiple banks such as Denizbank, HSBC, OdeaBank, and PTT
- Contributed to the common ATM project to handle functional requirements
- Participated in method analysis and process planning for the first-ever private bank common ATM integration with Denizbank
- Analyzed a project to improve consensus processes and help operation teams detect issues in master accounts or ATM cassette counters
- Worked on a customer feedback project that enabled customers to give feedback directly at the ATM in case of hardware malfunction, with the aim of improving customer satisfaction
- Analyzed and tested Denizbank's credit card bill payments with QR.

#### **Work Experience**

### Turkish Economy Bank - Business Analyst

https://teb.com.tr Istanbul, Turkey

Worked in the ATM team

- Contributed to the completion and deployment of all processes for the new ATM software
- Conducted device tests with Maestro at XFS layer
- Worked on testing ATM consensus processes and supply flows
- Performed NCR kernel certification tests for MasterCard and VISA
- Conducted general function tests, including cash withdrawal/deposit, credit card, and Notonus flows
- Analyzed journal data and ATM operation logs at back-office screens to deliver meaningful data to operation teams
- Worked on the analysis of refunds, including when and how they should be made and the acceleration of inadvance refunds to improve customer satisfaction.

#### **OBSS - Business Analyst**

January 2017 - December 2018

December 2018 - November 2020

https://obss.tech Istanbul, Turkey

Consultant at Turkish Economy Bank (TEB) in the ATM team

- Involved in the Aquila Tucana project, testing withdrawing, depositing, credit card flows, login processes with hand vein tracking, and billing transactions
- Participated in the analysis and testing of the monitoring screen and identification of the ATM terminal on back-office screens
- Created receipt templates for customers at compass and self-service applications
- Prepared analysis documents related to Bantaş OMS screens for improvements and new requests resulting from joint meetings with Asset Management, ATM ops, and Bantaş teams
- Participated in the new infrastructure project (Wincor) tests of the Optimus project
- Worked on testing many flows such as withdrawal cash advances, installment cash advance, sending withdrawing money from TEB, credit card functions, accounts, and one number update.

### **Education**

#### Bahçeşehir University - Executive MBA - Master's Degree

October 2021 - February 2023

Completed the business administration for executives program to improve management skills

Kristianstad University - Computer Science - Exchange Program

October 2013 - September 2014

Studied for a year in Sweeden with Erasmus exchange program, learned Android development using Greenfoot

Istanbul Aydın University - Software Engineering - Bachelor's Degree

**September 2011 - June 2016** 

Acquired theoretical and practical knowledge of computer science and software engineering, was vice president of IEEE student club, completed multiple projects and internships

### Skills

Java	HTTP/REST APIs	JUnit	SQL	HTML
CSS	JavaScript/TypeScript	React	git	Docker
Agile/SCRUM	TDD	CI/CD	Azure	Figma

#### **Projects**

stor-E July 2023

AI Powered Interactive Children Story Book Generator

# https://github.com/ascendio-stor-E

This application generates a story book for children, based on their selections. It uses OpenAI APIs to generate story texts and images. It is written in Java and Typescript. It uses Spring Framework on backend and React on frontend.

#### **International Karate Game**

Term Project from Kristianstad University

I developed it using Greenfoot.

## **INR Tracking Application**

Term Project from İstanbul Aydın University Junior Year

It is an application to monitor blood values of a patient. It allows navigating to the nearest hospital and calling for help in case of emergencies.

# **Smart Home & Office**

Final Project from İstanbul Aydın University

It is a mobile application. It lets you control the lights and power, get notified when there is an outage or danger, locking/unlocking the doors. It utilizes NFC tags placed in your home and office.

### Volunteering

# IEEE İstanbul Aydın University

Vice president of IEEE student club

# Düşün Taşın Derneği

Non-profit organization

#### Certifications

#### Full-Stack Java Bootcamp

May 2023 - July 2023

SALT

# https://salt.dev

Intensive three month training program for full stack web development with a focus on TDD, mob programming, and applied learning

# EMV

**BKM** 

# **Test & Certification Processes**

BKM

# Gamified Agile/SCRUM

ACM

# **Client Needs & Software Requirements**

Udacity

#### Java & Android

BilgeAdam

#### Languages

Turkish English

Native Professional